## **LUBERN FIGARO**

617-415-3290 | Lubernfigaro5@gmail.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Devops/Cloud Engineer with 3+ years of experience in Cloud/Automation environments, including: cloud orchestration, security, identity & access management, monitoring and event management, application delivery, data protection, image and patch management, self-service, and ops analytics on AWS platforms.

# **EXPERIENCE**

## JJ Tech | DevOps Engineer

January 2021 - Present

- Managed provisioning of AWS infrastructures using CloudFormation, Ansible and Terraform.
- Implemented continuous integration and deployment pipelines using Jenkins and Github.
- Developed solution designs to meet system strategies, capabilities, and technologies as per business requirements.
- Collaborated with development and operations teams to develop practical automation solutions and custom modules.
- Built a Multi-Tier, Highly Available, Fault-Tolerant Web Application.
- Configured API Gateway: Linked POST method to LambdaFunctionOverHttps for secure DynamoDBManager resource execution.
- Developed CI/CD to standardize the infrastructure and automated the DevOps processes, allowing customers to rapidly build, test, and release code while minimizing errors.
- Improved code deploy time for web applications by 70% enhancing the organization's application deployment process.
- Built a Fortune Teller application using AWS Lambda and API Gateway, that responds to user questions.
- Maximized email throughput via Lambda integration with AWS SES and SNS.

### CHA | Cloud Engineer

September 2020 - January 2021

- Built virtual data center in AWS Cloud to support Enterprise Data Warehouse hosting, including Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), Public and Private Subnets, Security Groups, NACLs, Route Tables, Elastic Load Balancers, VPC endpoints, Peering Connections, Transit Gateways, Route 53.
- Leveraged AWS cloud services (i.e. EC2, auto-scaling and VPC) to build secure, highly scalable, and flexible systems that handled expected and unexpected load bursts.
- Responsible for bucket creation, user account creation, access permission and privileges to users as well as policies and IAM role-based policies.
- Integrated an Amazon Lex ChatBot with Facebook Messenger, creating a responsive conversational interface.
- Implemented and maintained monitors, alarms, and notifications for EC2 instances using CloudWatch & SNS.
- Enabled Cloud Trail across all geographic regions and AWS services to prevent activity monitoring gaps.
- Developed, tested & implemented robust database backup and recovery strategy in line with client disaster.
- Created data visualizations using Amazon S3 and Amazon Quicksight, working with a large dataset of best-selling Amazon products.
- Deployed and hosted a highly-available WordPress application using EC2, RDS, Route 53, ASG and VPC.
- Built and maintained network infrastructure consisting of Windows, Linux and virtual products.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Wisconsin - Madison

May 2018

### Bachelor of Science, Human Development & Family Studies

• Leadership: Varsity Football Team (2014-2018), Varsity Football MVP (2018)

# **SKILLS**

AWS, CICD Pipeline, Terraform, Cloud Formation, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Sonarqube, Nexus, GitHub, Python, Java, Maven, Cloud Orchestration, Security Identity & Access Management, Monitoring And Event Management, Amazon S3, Disaster Recovery, and RDS.